Wyatt Wood

www.wyattwood.me • wyatt.wood@queensu.ca • (613) 331-2756

PROFILE

I am a hard-working, responsible student completing my 2nd year of University. I have 2+ years of combined academic experience writing software in Java, C, and MATLAB. Through academic and extra-curricular projects I have proven that I am a competent programmer that works effectively independently, as well as in a team setting.

EDUCATION

B.SC., Computer Engineering, 2014-2018 (Anticipated) Queen's University, Canada

SOFTWARE PROFICIENCIES

C, Java, Arduino, Assembly Language, HTML & CSS, Microsoft Word, Excel and PowerPoint, NESDAtrak, VHDL

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Seniors Outreach Services

Office Intern | Napanee, ON | June - Aug 2015

- Improved team efficiency by producing a Microsoft Excel overview, and revising the NESDAtrak user manual created by a previous employee.
- o Updated 300+ client profiles solving errors in the NESDAtrak database.
- Consulted upgrading to current operating system and Microsoft Office versions for performance enhancements and fewer incompatibilities on company computers.
- Entered statistical data into the NESDAtrak database to see which programs were profitable.
- o Entered financial data using Microsoft Dynamics GP to keep track of revenue.
- o Interacted with clients while working as a receptionist.

Computer Science II

Queen's University | Feb 2016 - Apr 2016

 Modelled the path and visuals of a projectile using coding practices that comply with Google's coding standards.

Visual Toolbox

Queen's University | Nov - Dec 2015

- o Generated creative ideas for applications that would be beneficial to visually impaired people.
- Wrote concise reports investigating the financial and societal impacts of the application.
- Created the preliminary user interface and the touch gestures associated with it.
- o Presented and demonstrated the final application in a team of 4 to an audience and a panel of judges.

Fundamentals of Information Structure

Queen's University | Feb 2015 - Apr 2016

o Applied advanced data structures and algorithms to solve complex laboratory problems in C.

Applied Science I

Queen's University | Sep 2014 - Jan 2015

- Predicted safety factors of sagging electrical wires, and optimal air flow through an enthalpy wheel using a mathematical model in MATLAB.
- Collected laboratory data to further improve models.

Professional Website

Developer, Designer | Kingston, ON | Nov 2015 - Jan 2016

o Using my knowledge of HTML and CSS, I designed a professional, attractive website in 3 months.

Shoppers Drug Mart

Merchandiser | Kingston, ON | July-Aug 2014

- o Built relationships with customers to ensure future business.
- Learned the layout of the store, and location of specific items quickly to prove useful to customers, and Shopper's Drug Mart.

RELEVANT SKILLS

- Excellent communication skills, developed through experience in customer service, and front desk reception.
- Highly critical thinker with effective researching skills proven academically through open-ended problem solving.
- Proven time management and organization skills by managing multiple team projects at once and submitting high quality work.